Private detective Easy Rawlins has been caught on the wrong
side of the most dangerous secret in town.
Devil in a Blue Dress is a thriller, crime,
mystery film directed by Carl Franklin.
In late 1940s Los Angeles, Easy Rawlins is an unemployed black
World War II veteran with few job prospects.
At a bar, Easy meets DeWitt Albright, a mysterious white man looking for someone to investigate the disappearance of a
missing white woman named Daphne Monet, who he suspects is hiding out in one of the city's black jazz clubs.
Strapped for money and facing house payments, Easy takes the
job, but soon finds himself in over his head.
Easy Rawlins, played by Denzel Washington.
DeWitt Albright, played by Tom Sizemore.
Daphne Monet, played by Jennifer Beals.
Mouse Alexander, played by Don Cheadle.
Matthew Terell, played by Maury Chaykin.
Todd Carter, played by Terry Kinney.
Devil in a Blue Dress is a 1995 American neo-noir mystery thriller film written and directed by Carl Franklin, based on Walter
Mosley's 1990 novel of the same name and features Denzel Washington, Tom Sizemore, Jennifer Beals, and Don Cheadle.
Set in 1948, the film follows World War II veteran Ezekiel "Easy" Rawlins who,
desperately in need of a job, becomes drawn into a search for a mysterious woman.
Devil in a Blue Dress received positive reviews, with
many praising Cheadle's performance.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, war
veteran, jazz club, murder, los angeles, california.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.